Get touched by an angel.
Dogma is a fantasy, comedy, adventure film directed by Kevin Smith.
An abortion clinic worker with a special heritage is called upon to save the existence of humanity from
being negated by two renegade angels trying to exploit a loophole and reenter Heaven.
Bartleby, played by Ben Affleck.
Loki, played by Matt Damon.
Bethany, played by Linda Fiorentino.
Serendipity, played by Salma Hayek Pinault.
Azrael, played by Jason Lee.
Jay, played by Jason Mewes.
Dogma is a 1999 American fantasy comedy film written,
co-edited, and directed by Kevin Smith.
The film stars Ben Affleck, Matt Damon, Linda Fiorentino, Salma Hayek,
Jason Lee, Jason Mewes, Alan Rickman, and Chris Rock.
It is the fourth film in the View Askewniverse.
The story revolves around two fallen angels who plan to employ an alleged loophole in Catholic dogma to return to Heaven after being cast out by God,
but as existence is founded on the principle that God is infallible, their success would prove God wrong, thus undoing all creation.
The last descendant of Jesus Christ and two prophets are
sent by the angel Metatron to stop them.
Dogma screened out of competition at the 1999 Cannes Film Festival on May 21, 1999, and
was released in the United States on November 12 by Lions Gate Films.
The film's irreverent treatment of Catholicism and the Catholic Church
triggered considerable controversy, even before its opening.
The Catholic League denounced it as blasphemy.
Organized protests delayed its release in many countries and
led to at least two death threats against Smith.
Despite this, Dogma received generally positive reviews from critics, and grossed $45 million against its $10
million budget, becoming the highest-grossing film in the View Askewniverse series to date.
The film explores themes of angel, wisconsin, dark
comedy, satire, church service.
The tone is lighthearted and dark.